Joe Kowan: I have stage fright.
جوي كووان: لدي رهاب المسرح.
I've always had stage fright,
لقد عانيت دائماً منه،
and not just a little bit,
و ليس بشكل طفيف،
it's a big bit.
إنما بشكل كبير.
And it didn't even matter until I was 27.
و لم يكن الأمر مهم بالنسبة لي حتى عمر ال27.
That's when I started writing songs, and even then
هنا حين بدأت بتأليف الأغاني، و مع ذلك
I only played them for myself.
لقد عزفتها لنفسي فقط.
Just knowing my roommates were in the same house made me uncomfortable.
مجرد معرفتي أن زملائي بالسكن موجودين بالمنزل كان يجعلني متوتر.
But after a couple of years, just writing songs wasn't enough.
لكن بعد بضعة سنوات، تأليف الأغاني وحده لم يعد كافياً.
I had all these stories and ideas, and I wanted to share them with people,
كانت عندي كل هذه القصص و الأفكار، و أردت أن أشارك الناس بها،
but physiologically, I couldn't do it.
لكن من الناحية الجسمية، لم أكن قادر على ذلك.
I had this irrational fear.
كان لدي هذا الخوف الغير منطقي.
But the more I wrote, and the more I practiced,
لكن كلما كتبت أكثر، و كلما تدربت،
the more I wanted to perform.
كلما زادت رغبتي بالأداء.
So on the week of my 30th birthday,
فهكذا في أسبوع عيد ميلادي ال30،
I decided I was going to go to this local open mic,
قررت أنني سوف أذهب إلى هذا المقهى المحلي للأداء الحر،
and put this fear behind me.
و سوف أتخطى هذا الخوف.
Well, when I got there, it was packed.
حسناً، عندما وصلت إلى هناك، لقد كان المكان مزدحم.
There were like 20 people there.
لقد كان هناك حوالي 20 شخص هناك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And they all looked angry.
و بدا جميعهم غاضب.
But I took a deep breath, and I signed up to play,
لكني أخذت نفس عميق، و سجلّت للتقديم،
and I felt pretty good.
و شعرت بشعور جيد جداً.
Pretty good, until about 10 minutes before my turn,
جيد جداً، حتى حوالي ال10 دقائق قبل دوري،
when my whole body rebelled, and this wave of anxiety just washed over me.
حينما تمرّد كل جسمي، و اعترتني موجة القلق هذه.
Now, when you experience fear, your sympathetic nervous system kicks in.
الآن، عندما تصاب بالخوف، يبدأ جهازك العصبي السمبثاوي بالعمل.
So you have a rush of adrenaline, your heart rate increases,
فيزداد الأدرنالين، و يتسارع نبض قلبك،
your breathing gets faster.
و يزيد معدل تنفسك.
Next your non-essential systems start to shut down, like digestion. (Laughter)
ثم تبدأ أجهزتك الحيوية الأخرى بالتوقف عن العمل، كالهضم. (ضحك)
So your mouth gets dry, and blood is routed away from your extremities,
فيصاب فمك بالجفاف، و يتوقف وصول الدم إلى الأطراف.
so your fingers don't work anymore.
فتتوقف أصابعك عن العمل.
Your pupils dilate, your muscles contract, your Spidey sense tingles,
يتوسع بؤبؤا عينيك، تتقلص عضلاتك، تشعر بأنك &amp;quot;سبيدي&amp;quot; (بطل مجلات مصورة)،
basically your whole body is trigger-happy. (Laughter)
أي يصبح جسمك متحمس جداً. (ضحك)
That condition is not conducive to performing folk music.
تلك الحالة لا تساعد على أداء الموسيقى الشعبية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I mean, your nervous system is an idiot.
أعني، إن جهازك العصبي غبي.
Really? Two hundred thousand years of human evolution, and it still can't tell the difference
حقاً؟ ألفا سنة من تطور البشر، و لا يزال لا يستطيع التفرقة
between a saber tooth tiger and 20 folksingers
بين نمر ذي أنياب كبيرة و 20 من المغنيين الشعبيين
on a Tuesday night open mic?
في ليلة الأداء الحر يوم الثلاثاء؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I have never been more terrified -- until now.
لم يسبق لي أن كنت أكثر خوفاً -- حتى الآن.
(Laughter and cheers)
(تصفيق و هتاف)
So then it was my turn,
ثم حلّ دوري،
and somehow, I get myself onto the stage, I start my song,
و بطريقة ما، تمالكت نفسي و صعدت على المسرح، بدأت بأغنيتي،
I open my mouth to sing the first line,
فقتحت فمي لأغني البيت الأول،
and this completely horrible vibrato --
و هذا الاهتزاز الرهيب كلياً --
you know, when your voice wavers -- comes streaming out.
تعرف، كيف يرتعش صوتك -- بدأ بالخروج.
And this is not the good kind of vibrato, like an opera singer has,
و هذا ليس من النوع المحبب من الاهتزاز، كالذي يمتلكه مغني أوبرا،
this is my whole body just convulsing with fear.
إن جسمي يرتعش بأكمله من الخوف.
I mean, it's a nightmare.
أعني، إنه كابوس.
I'm embarrassed, the audience is clearly uncomfortable,
كنت محرج، و بدا الجمهور منزعج بشكل واضح،
they're focused on my discomfort.
كل تركيزهم كان على توتري.
It was so bad.
لقد كان الوضع سيء جداً.
But that was my first real experience as a solo singer-songwriter.
لكن هذه كانت تجربتي الأولى الواقعية كمغني فردي و مؤلف أغاني.
And something good did happen -- I had the tiniest little glimpse
و أمر جيد قد حصل -- لقد حصلت على فكرة
of that audience connection that I was hoping for.
عن التواصل مع الجمهور الذي كنت أريده.
And I wanted more. But I knew I had to get past this nervousness.
و أردت المزيد. لكني عرفت أنني بحاجة إلى تخطي هذا التوتر.
That night I promised myself: I would go back every week
في تلك الليلة قطعت على نفسي وعداً: سوف أعود كل أسبوع
until I wasn't nervous anymore.
إلى أن أتخلص من التوتر.
And I did. I went back every single week,
و فعلت. عدت كل أسبوع،
and sure enough, week after week,
و بالطبع، أسبوع بعد أسبوع،
it didn't get any better. The same thing happened every week. (Laughter)
لم يتحسن الأمر بتاتاً. لقد تكرر الأمر كل أسبوع. (ضحك)
I couldn't shake it.
لم أستطع التخلص منه.
And that's when I had an epiphany.
و هنا حصل لي تجلي.
And I remember it really well, because I don't have a lot of epiphanies. (Laughter)
و أذكر ذلك جيداً جداً، لأن ذلك لا يحصل كثيراً. (ضحك)
All I had to do was write a song that exploits my nervousness.
كل ما كان علي فعله هو كتابة أغنية تستغل توتري.
That only seems authentic when I have stage fright,
الأغنية الوحيدة التي تبدو صادقة عندما أصاب برهاب المسرح،
and the more nervous I was,
و كلما زاد توتري،
the better the song would be. Easy.
كلما كان أداء الأغنية أفضل. أمر سهل.
So I started writing a song about having stage fright.
لذا بدأت بكتابة أغنية عن المعاناة من رهاب المسرح.
First, fessing up to the problem,
في البداية، الإقرار بالمشكلة،
the physical manifestations, how I would feel,
العوارض الجسمية، كيفية شعوري،
how the listener might feel.
كيف قد يشعر المستمع.
And then accounting for things like my shaky voice,
و أيضاً الأخذ بعين الاعتبار أشياء كصوتي المهتز،
and I knew I would be singing about a half-octave higher than normal,
و لقد علمت أني سوف أغني حوالي نصف جواب موسيقي أعلى من العادة،
because I was nervous.
لأني كنت متوتر.
By having a song that explained what was happening to me,
بوجود أغنية تفسر ما الذي كان يحدث لي،
while it was happening,
بينما كان يحدث لي،
that gave the audience permission to think about it.
قد أعطى للجمهور الإذن للتفكير به.
They didn't have to feel bad for me because I was nervous,
لم يكونوا بحاجة لأن يشعروا بالسوء حيال توتري،
they could experience that with me,
كانوا قادرين على الشعور به معي،
and we were all one big happy, nervous, uncomfortable family. (Laughter)
و جميعنا كنا عائلة واحدة كبيرة، متوترة،و منزعجة. (ضحك)
By thinking about my audience, by embracing and exploiting my problem,
بالتفكير بجمهوري، بتقبّلي و استغلال مشكلتي،
I was able to take something that was blocking my progress,
لقد كنت قادراً على أخذ شيء كان يعيق تقدمي،
and turn it into something that was essential for my success.
و تحويله إلى شيء أصبح أساسي في نجاحي.
And having the stage fright song let me get past that biggest issue
و كتابتي لأغنية رهاب المسرح سمح لي بتخطي هذه المشكلة الكبيرة جداً
right in the beginning of a performance.
التي تحصل في بداية الأداء.
And then I could move on, and play the rest of my songs
و ثم استطعت المضي قدماً، و أداء بقية أغانيي
with just a little bit more ease.
مع القليل جداً من الراحة.
And eventually, over time, I didn't have to play the stage fright song at all.
و في النهاية، مع مرور الوقت، لم أعد بحاجة إلى أن أغني أغنية رهاب المسرح أبداً.
Except for when I was really nervous, like now. (Laughter)
باستثناء عندما أكون متوتراً جداً، كالآن. (ضحك)
Would it be okay if I played the stage fright song for you?
هل من الممكن أن أؤدي أغنية رهاب المسرح لأجلكم؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Can I have a sip of water?
هل يمكنني الحصول على رشفة ماء؟
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Thank you.
شكراً.
♫ I'm not joking, you know, ♫
♫إنني لا أمزح، أتعلمون♫
♫ this stage fright is real. ♫
♫ رهاب المسرح هذا حقيقي. ♫
♫ And if I'm up here trembling and singing, ♫
♫ و إن كنت في الأعلى هنا أرتجف و أغني، ♫
♫ well, you'll know how I feel. ♫
♫ حسناً، سوف تعلمون كيف أشعر. ♫
♫ And the mistake I'd be making, ♫
♫ و الأخطاء التي سوف أقترفها، ♫
♫ the tremolo caused by my whole body shaking. ♫
♫ الاهتزاز الذي سببه ارتعاش كل جسمي ♫
♫ As you sit there feeling embarrassed for me, ♫
♫ بينما أنتم تجلسون هنا تشعرون بالاحراج لأجلي، ♫
♫ well, you don't have to be. ♫
♫ حسناً، أنتم لستم بحاجة لأن تفعلوا ذلك. ♫
♫ Well, maybe just a little bit. ♫
♫ حسناً، قليلاً من الممكن. ♫
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
♫ And maybe I'll try to imagine you all without clothes. ♫
♫ و ربما سأحاول تخيلكم جميعاً عراة ♫
♫ But singing in front of all naked strangers scares me more than anyone knows. ♫
♫ لكن الغناء أمام غرباء عراة يرعبني أكثر مما أحد يتصور. ♫
♫ Not to discuss this at length, ♫
♫ لن أشرح هذا مطولاً، ♫
♫ but my body image was never my strength. ♫
♫ لكن ثقتي بشكلي لم تكن أبداً مصدر قوتي. ♫
♫ So frankly, I wish that you all would get dressed, ♫
♫ لذا بصراحة، أتمنى أن ترتدوا جميعكم ملابس، ♫
♫ I mean, you're not even really naked. ♫
♫ أعني، إنكم حتى لستم عراة حقاً. ♫
♫ And I'm the one with the problem. ♫
♫ و أنا الشخص صاحب المشكلة. ♫
♫ And you tell me, don't worry so much, you'll be great. ♫
♫ و تقولون لي، لا تقلق كثيراً، سوف تكون رائعاً. ♫
♫ But I'm the one living with me ♫
♫ لكني أنا الذي أعيش مع نفسي ♫
♫ and I know how I get. ♫
♫ و أعلم كيف أصبح. ♫
♫ Your advice is gentle but late. ♫
♫ نصيحتكم لطيفة لكنها متأخرة. ♫
♫ If not just a bit patronizing. ♫
♫ هذا إن لم تكن متعالية قليلاً. ♫
♫ And that sarcastic tone doesn't help me when I sing. ♫
♫ و هذه النبرة الساخرة لا تساعدني عندما أغني. ♫
♫ But we shouldn't talk about these things right now, ♫
♫ لكن لا يجب علينا أن نتكلم عن هذه الأمور الآن، ♫
♫ really, I'm up on stage, and you're in the crowd. Hi. ♫
♫ حقاً، إني على المسرح، و أنتم الحضور. مرحباً. ♫
♫ And I'm not making fun of unnurtured, irrational fear, ♫
♫ و إني لست أسخر من خوف منطقي، يحميني، ♫
♫ and if I wasn't ready to face this, ♫
♫ و إن لم أكن جاهزأً لمواجهة هذا، ♫
♫ I sure as hell wouldn't be here. ♫
♫ من المؤكد ما كنت لأكون هنا. ♫
♫ But if I belt one note out clearly, ♫
♫ لكني إن نشّذت بنغمة بشكل واضح، ♫
♫ you'll know I'm recovering slowly but surely. ♫
♫ سوف تعلمون أنني أتعافى ببطء لكن بثبات. ♫
♫ And maybe next week, I'll set my guitar ringin' ♫
♫ و لربما في الأسبوع القادم، قد أستطيع أن أعزف على جيتاري ♫
♫ my voice clear as water, and everyone singin'. ♫
♫ و صوتي نقي نقاء الماء، و الجميع يغني. ♫
♫ But probably I'll just get up and start groovin', ♫
♫ لكني على الأغلب سوف أقف و أبدأ بالغناء، ♫
♫ my vocal cords movin', ♫
♫ و أحبالي الصوتية تتحرك، ♫
♫ at speeds slightly faster than sound. ♫
♫ بسرعات أعلى بقليل من الصوت. ♫
(Applause)
(تصفيق)